#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/aldenmahabir (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Investment Banking Equity Research Equities

#### Certifications

Chartered Financial Analyst (CFA) - Level II Candidate

# Alden Mahabir

Strategy & Investment Executive

Basking Ridge, New Jersey, United States

## Summary

Two-time entrepreneur and enduring student of business. Spent ~20 years creating, growing, turning around, and evaluating businesses. As a corporate strategist, I created tactics that focused on scaling products/revenues at a Fortune 20 corporation, while developing plans to maximize a declining legacy business. As a corporate venture capitalist for the same corporation, I spent 5 years evaluating and investing in technology startups, while also conducting internal and external business development for the portfolio companies. As an investment banker and equity research analyst on Wall Street, advised on multibillion-dollar M&A transactions, public and private equity investments, and bankruptcy restructurings. Co-founded a media and telecom-focused investment research firm at age 25 and a real estate brokerage at 19.

## Experience

Verizon

Director - Strategy & Planning October 2018 - Present (4 years 7 months)

Basking Ridge, New Jersey

Develop(ing) strategies for Verizon's B2B Group (\$31B in revenues), that maximize the firm's investments in 5G wireless, 5G Edge/Cloud, IoT, UCaaS, fiber, and other technologies.

Led governance activities for the B2B Group in preparation for Board of Directors meetings, Operational Reviews, Investor Communications and Meetings, etc.

Developed a comprehensive strategy for Verizon's wholesale wireline business (\$3B in revenue), that helped to establish it as the #3 fiber provider.

Evaluated over 150 commercial deals on behalf of the B2B Group and Wholesale unit which ranges from assets swaps, joint builds, IoT connectivity, long-haul/metro fiber, subsea consortiums, among others.

Evaluate and execute investments, M&A, and strategic partnerships with startups and large companies.

Verizon Ventures
Verizon Ventures
July 2013 - October 2018 (5 years 4 months)
Greater New York City Area

Evaluated and led investments that were strategic to Verizon's core businesses. Areas included IoT, Digital Media, e-Commerce & Payments, Advertising, Mobile, AR/VR, eSports, Data & Analytics, among others.

Produced intelligence reports on disruptive startups, burgeoning industries, and emerging trends that guide the firm's investment thesis and focus. Reports not only provide insights for the ventures team, but also provides a channel to bring intelligence back to the business.

Worked closely with the corporate strategy team to explore and develop new areas of growth.

Hosted closed-door forums which bring together executives from Verizon, startups, VCs and corporate peers, to discuss the future of nascent industries and emerging trends - a conduit for deal flow, partnerships, and insights.

Supported Verizon Ventures' portfolio companies with internal and external business development.

Helped craft and develop the firm's marketing and messaging strategy, aimed at startups, co-investors and internal Verizon constituents.

Goodrich Capital LLC Advisor to CEO 2011 - 2013 (2 years)

Advised startup and growth companies on their business strategy, as well as helped them raise venture and/or growth equity capital.

Assisted the firm with M&A engagements, which includes valuation and financial modeling, pairing targets and acquirers, and structuring deals.

Utendahl Capital Partners Senior Vice President 2007 - 2008 (1 year)

Founded the firm's media & telecom equity research practice, which required establishing new institutional investor and corporate clients.

#### **CIBC World Markets**

Director 2006 - 2007 (1 year)

Covered the media & entertainment industry. Duties included financial modeling, writing industry and company-specific research, and assisting with investor and sales force inquiries.

Vintage Research
Managing Director / Partner
2003 - 2005 (2 years)

Co-founded an investment research and consulting firm focused on the media, cable, and telecom sectors. Forged an exclusive partnership with Janney Montgomery Scott that wedded Vintage's research with Janney's sales, trading and investment banking platform.

Lehman Brothers Senior Associate 2001 - 2003 (2 years)

Member of the satellite communications equity research team, which placed 3rd in the 2003 Greenwich Associates rankings and 6th in the 2002 Institutional Investor rankings. In both surveys, the team ranked #1 for industry knowledge, written product, analysis detail, and most trusted, while achieving #2 for stock selection.

C.E. Unterberg, Towbin Analyst 1998 - 2001 (3 years)

Solicited and executed investment banking transactions within the aerospace, satellite communications, and media industries. Transactions included equity and debt offerings, M&A, divestitures, and restructurings.

Good Buy Realty Co-Founder 1997 - 1999 (2 years) Greater New York City Area

Co-founded a real estate brokerage firm at the age of 19, after working as a New York state licensed real estate agent at two Century 21 franchises.

## Education

NYU Stern School of Business

Master of Business Administration - MBA, Leadership, Entrepreneurship, & Finance  $\cdot$  (2010 - 2012)

Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey-New Brunswick BA, Economics; Minor - Biology · (1996 - 2000)